kryolan.com 2015-03-22

# Privacy Policy | Kryolan - Professional Make-up

Last Updated: 11/01/2013

Kryolan Corporation ( _“Kryolan or “we” “our” or “us”_ ) respect your privacy, and we are committed to letting you know how we will collect and use your personal information. This privacy policy ( _“Privacy Policy”_ ) informs you of our privacy practices, how we collect and use your information, when it might be disclosed, and how you can manage your personal information while accessing or using our network of websites, all email newsletters published or distributed by us, all apps published by us, and all other interactive features, services, and communications provided by us ( _“Website”_ ), however accessed or used, that are operated by us, made available by us, or produced and maintained by us. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Websites. It does not apply to information that you may submit to us offline, or to Websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to Kryolan’s terms of use ( _“Terms”_ ). Your use of the Website is subject to this Privacy Policy and the Terms. Capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy that are not otherwise defined have the meanings set forth in the Terms. This Privacy Policy is a legal agreement between you and Kryolan that states the material terms and conditions that govern your use of the Website. You agree to this Privacy Policy by accessing or using our Website. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS POLICY, DO NOT USE THE WEBSITE.

KRYOLAN MAY PERIODICALLY AND IN ITS SOLE DISCRETION MODIFY THIS POLICY. IF KRYOLAN MATERIALLY CHANGES THIS POLICY, A NOTICE WILL BE POSTED ON THE WEBSITE, ALONG WITH THE UPDATED POLICY, AND THE “LAST UPDATED” DATE ABOVE WILL BE MODIFIED. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE WEBSITE MEANS THAT YOU ACCEPT THE UPDATED POLICY. UNLESS WE PROVIDE YOU WITH SPECIFIC NOTICE, NO CHANGES TO OUR POLICY WILL APPLY RETROACTIVELY. 

## 1\. What Information Does Kryolan Collect and Store?

Our privacy policy is simple: except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we will not sell, barter, give away or rent your personal information to any other company. We collect two basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Website: personal information and non-personal information. _“Personal Information”_ is any information that can individually identify you, and includes, among other things, your name, e-mail address, telephone number, postal address, and credit card, billing and contact information. It also includes information that you may supply to us, as described more fully below, i.e., when you register for the Website, order from the Website, upload content, participate in a community, or provide your e-mail address. _“Non-Personal Information”_ includes information that does not personally identify you, but it may include tracking and usage information about your demographics, use of the Website and the Internet. 

### Personal Information.

As a general matter, you can browse the Website without submitting your Personal Information to us. However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may supply us with your Personal Information. The following lists the most common ways in which we may collect your Personal Information: 

  * Register for an account on the Website;
  * Sign up to receive e-mail newsletters, e-mail alerts, or email offers from us;
  * Respond to surveys related to the Website;
  * Place online orders through the Website;
  * Request customer service or other assistance;
  * Participate in special events, promotions, and contests;
  * Participate in social media accounts involving Kryolan content or services;
  * Participate in communities, chat rooms and comment threads, and other interactive services we may provide to you;
  * Submit a job application; or
  * Volunteer personal information to us in any other manner.

### Collection of Personal Information From or Through Social Media Sites or Using Your Social Media Login.

When you interact with any Kryolan page or account on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Tumblr, LinkedIn, YouTube, or Pinterest, we may collect the personal information that you make available to us on that page or account including your account ID or “handle.” However, we will comply with the privacy policies of the corresponding social media platform and we will only collect and store such personal information that we are permitted to collect by these social media platforms. If you choose to link or login to your Kryolan account with or through a social networking service, Kryolan and that service may share certain information about you and your activities, including your IP Address and that you have visited our Website. With your consent, we also may share information about your activities, including what you view on the Website, with that social network’s users. 

### Non-Personal Information.

When you interact with our Website, our servers may keep an activity log or our servers may automatically store Non-Personal Information that does not identify you individually. Generally, we collect and store the following categories of Non-Personal Information: 

  * Demographic data, such as age, gender, and your five-digit zip code, as part of collecting Personal Information;
  * Device information about your computer, mobile device, tablet or other technology (each a “Device”) that you use to access the Website. This information may include browser type, browser language, and other transaction information;
  * Usage information about your use of the Website, such as a reading history of the pages you view. We use this information to provide you a more customized experience of the Website;
  * Additional “traffic data” such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses;
  * Your search terms and search results; and
  * Other information regarding your use of the Website.

### Collection of Your Source IP Address / Location Information

We may collect and store your Device’s source IP address, which may disclose the location of your Device at the time you access the Website. Advertisements and certain content may be directed to you as a result of this data. In addition, in some cases the Website can deliver content based on your current location if you choose to enable that feature. If you enable that feature, your current location will be stored to serve you certain content tied to your location. If you elect to have your location-based searches saved to your history, we will store such information on our servers. 

### Collection of Personal and Non-Personal Information from Other Sources

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources (including our offline interactions with you), to, among other things, enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database and to better customize your experience on the Website. 

### Cookies and Spyware

Like many websites, we may use _“Cookies”_ , which are small text files that are stored on your Device when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences and actions. We use Cookies to track use of our Website and online services. We may also use Cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Website and make it easier or more relevant for your use.

Specifically, our Website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ( _“Google”_ ). Google Analytics uses Cookies, which collect information about your use of the Website (including your IP address), which is sent to a server of Google in the United States and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the Website, to prepare reports on the Website activities for us, and to perform additional services involving use of the Website and the Internet. Google will provide this information to third parties, insofar as such is legally stipulated. Google may not connect your IP address with other data by Google. By using our Website, you declare that you agree to the processing of data obtained about you by Google in the manner described above, and for the purpose as stated. You have the ability to accept or decline Cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept Cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline Cookies. If you delete your Cookies or if you set your web browser to decline Cookies, some features of the Website may not work or may not work as designed. For more information on Cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). We may also use web beacons or flash cookies. A web beacon or flash cookie (also known as “action tags”, “tracer tags”, or “single-pixel gifs”) is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect Non-Personal Information about your use of a given website. We do not share or provide Personal Information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers without your express permission. We may also use _“Web Storage”_ to store data about your use of our Website. Web Storage is a feature in some browsers that permits websites to store data within your browser rather than within a Cookie. This should make this data more secure and make your browser perform better. We do not share or provide Personal Information we may store in Web Storage, such as names and e-mail addresses, without your express permission. 

## 2\. Is Personal Information Collected From Children?

Our Website is not directed to children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13 years old. If you are under 13 years old, you should not use this Website, and under no circumstances should you send information about yourself to us without providing us with consent from your parents or legal guardian. If we become aware that we have received personal information from a visitor under the age of 13 on the site and we do not have parental consent or legal guardian consent, we will delete the information from our records. 

## 3\. How Does Kryolan Use Personal and Non-Personal Information?

We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Website. We may use your Personal and Non-Personal Information in the following ways: 

### General Uses

  * Provide you with the content and services you request;
  * Provide you with coupons and offers based upon your order history;
  * Provide you with order recommendations based on your order history;
  * Provide you with directions to and information about the Kryolan locations nearest to you;
  * Communicate with you about your account and send you information about features and enhancements on or to our Website and to our Kryolan locations;
  * Communicate with you about changes to our policies;
  * Personalize content and experiences on our Website, including providing you recommendations based on your preferences;
  * Send you newsletters, offers and promotions, by e-mail, text, or other medium
  * Send you order receipts by e-mail, text, or other medium;
  * Optimize or improve our services and operations;
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal; and
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Website.

### Use of Your Location Information

In addition, we may use your location information to: 

  * Provide you with Products you request;
  * Personalize content and experiences on our Website, including providing you recommendations based on your preferences;
  * Personalize newsletters, offers, and promotions;
  * Optimize or improve our Website;
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal; and
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analysis of users of the Website.

### Combination of Your Personal Information

We may use the information from one portion of the Website in other portions of the Website, and we may combine information gathered from multiple portions of the Website into a single customer record. We may also use or combine information that we collect off-line or that we receive from third party sources to enhance, expand, and check the accuracy of your customer records. 

## 4\. When Does Kryolan Disclose Your Information?

Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your Personal Information with third-party companies for their own commercial or marketing use without your prior consent. 

### Third-Party Agents

We have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting, billing, content syndication, content management tools, social media integration, marketing, analytics, customer service, fraud protection, etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Website. 

### Social Media and Third Party Websites

On our Website we have or may in the future integrate plugins from Facebook, Google +1, Twitter, YouTube, and other third parties. If you use one of these plugins, this will create a direct connection between your browser and that of the third party, and may provide them with information about your use of our Website, which you consent to by your use of the plugin. In addition, our Website contains links to external Websites of third parties, over which we have no control. We cannot therefore be held liable for the content of these external sites. These links and plugins are provided for your convenience, and they do not signify that we endorse the websites. The respective suppliers or operators of such sites are responsible for the content of such sites. Any activities you engage in involving linked websites or plugins are subject to privacy and other policies, terms and conditions of use, and other rules issued by the operator of the linked websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to those sites. Please consult the respective Web pages of the plugin for further information on the type, extent, and purpose of data recording and use of personally related data, and on the possible processing of such data 

### Business Partners

We may share your Personal Information with our business partners or co-marketers from time to time. Although our treatment of your Personal Information is governed by this Privacy Policy, the business partner’s treatment of your Personal Information will be governed by the business partner’s privacy policy. You may withdraw your consent to our sharing of your Personal Information with business partners at any time by following the opt-out process described below. We hereby expressly forbid the use of contact data by third parties within the context of our imprint obligation for the submission of not expressly solicited advertising and information material. The operator of this Website expressly reserves the right to take legal action in the case of provision of unrequested advertising (e.g., in the form of spam mail and the like). 

### Emergency Situations

We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Website or our users; and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Website or the public. 

### Use of Non-Personal Information

We may disclose or share Non-Personal Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose Non-Personal Information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and how to improve our Website. We will also disclose Non-Personal Information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Website. 

## 5\. Security

### Security of Personal Information

Personal data provided within the context of an order or as part of our other service offerings are protected by technical security systems and additional authorization procedures. While we use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your information, we are not liable for disclosure of any information due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties. No data storage system or transmission method is guaranteed to be 100% secure, and as a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you may supply. If Kryolan learns of a security breach, we may attempt to notify you so that you can take appropriate protective steps. 

### Your Obligation to Keep Access Rights Secure

You promise to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself as prompted by the Website’s registration form (such information being the _“Registration Data”_ ) and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or Kryolan has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, Kryolan has the right to suspend or terminate your account and refuse any and all current or future use of the Website (or any portion thereof). You are entirely responsible for the security and confidentiality of your password and account. Furthermore, you are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account. 

## 6\. Data Transfers

We may transfer the Personal Information we collect to countries other than the country in which you are located. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information, and by voluntarily submitting Personal Information to us, you thereby consent to the transfer of that information to, and / or storage of that information in, the United States. 

## 7\. Assignment

Kryolan may change its ownership or corporate organization while providing the Website. As a result, please be aware that Kryolan may transfer your information to another company that is affiliated with Kryolan or with which Kryolan has merged or been acquired by. Under such circumstances we would, to the extent possible, require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Nevertheless, we cannot promise that an acquiring company or the merged company will have the same privacy practices or treat your information the same as described in this Privacy Policy. 

## 8\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

As our Website continues to develop, we may add new services and features to our Website. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use our Website in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy. We will not, however, materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of Personal Information we have previously collected from you without your express consent. 

## 9\. How to Opt-Out of Sharing Your Personal Information; How to Correct Personal Information

### Opt-Out

You always may opt-out of receiving future e-mail messages and newsletters. Kryolan provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about you. To remove your Personal Information from our database, to not receive future communications or to no longer receive services from us, send an e-mail to [webshop-usa@kryolan.com](mailto:webshop-usa@kryolan.com) with the word “remove” in the subject line. Kryolan also permits you to correct or update Personal Information that you have previously provided to us. To do so, send e-mail to: [webshop-usa@kryolan.com](mailto:webshop-usa@kryolan.com) indicating the information that you wish to be corrected or updated. 

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Kryolan who are California residents to request certain information regarding Kryolan’s disclosure of their Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [webshop-usa@kryolan.com](mailto:webshop-usa@kryolan.com).

Thank you for visiting our Website. We hope you enjoy your visit.
